Rémy Leroy, PhD

rmyleroy@gmail.com | https://rmyleroy.github.io/

Engineer and scientific researcher specialised in image processing and computer vision, with a strong intuitive grasp of visual signal interpretation and a unique interdisciplinary profile bridging optics, physics, and deep learning. Skilled in developing maintainable, well-structured code, and driven by a fundamental need to understand underlying mechanisms. Naturally inquisitive, values clarity, simplicity, and reproducibility in algorithm design.

Skill

- Machine Learning
- Computer Vision
- Computational Photography

- Scientific Peer Review
- Clean and Maintainable code
- Python/Pytorch

Work Experience

Post-doctoral researcher @ INRIA, France | 2023/04 - 2024/08

Explored **signal compression** techniques using **Implicit Neural Representations**, with a focus on Light Field image data.

PhD candidate in signal and image processing @ ONERA, France | 2019/03 - 2023/03

Gained deep expertise in state-of-the-art methods for **image processing** and **computer vision**. Designed and implemented deep neural networks using **PyTorch** for **monocular 3D vision**. Proposed a novel **depth estimation** method that exploits **defocus blur** in single-image inputs. Developed an end-to-end framework for the **joint optimisation** of optical components and neural networks.

Published and presented original research in peer-reviewed international journals and conferences.

Research intern @ CEA, France | 2017/09 - 2018/03

Developed an iterative algorithm for removing transformation artefacts in dark matter mass mapping in **Python**

Education

2023 - Paris-Saclay University, France | Doctorate in Signal and Image Processing

2019 - IMT Atlantique (Institut Mines-Telecom), France | Master's degree in Engineering

2019 - IMT Atlantique and Rennes 1 University, France | MSc in Electronic and Automation

Publications

Multitask deep co-design for extended depth of field and depth from defocus.

M. Dufraisse, R. Leroy, P. Trouvé-Peloux, F. Champagnat, J.-B. Volatier

Proc. SPIE 12996, Unconventional Optical Imaging IV, June 2024

Learning local depth regression from defocus blur by soft-assignment encoding.

R. Leroy, P. Trouvé-Peloux, B. Le Saux, B. Buat et F. Champagnat.

Applied Optics, vol.61, n°29, p.8843--8849. 2022

Pix2Point: Learning Outdoor 3D Using Sparse Point Clouds and Optimal Transport.

R. Leroy, P. Trouvé-Peloux, F. Champagnat, B. Le Saux, M. Carvlho.

Int. Conf. on Machine Vision and Applications (MVA), Oct 2021